# Mary Ellen Kelly

### CONTACT

811 Dunlewy Street Asbury Park, NJ 07712 E: mekelly316@gmail.com P: 732.768.8120

#### **EDUCATION**

MBA: Marketing & Strategic Management Villanova University | 2013

BA: Strategic & Organizational Communications Temple University | 2008

Certificate: Digital Marketing Temple University | In process

#### **SKILLS**

PhotoShop
Basic HTML
Critical Impact
Airnet (CMS)
PowerPoint
Word
Excel
Outlook
Streamline (WorksmartSuite)

#### REFERENCES

Doug Sherman VP Marketing Communications Airgas | 610.397.2818 doug.sherman@airgas.com

> Sarah Boxler Communications Manager Airgas | 215.495.8439 sarahsboxler@gmail.com

Liz Hostetter Account Manager (formerly) RR Donnelly | 215.776.6740 liz.m.hostetter@gmail.com

#### ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Passport to Leadership The Copywriter's Workshop Direct Marketing Institute

### **PROFILE**

Strategic Marketing and Communications professional with strong integrated marketing experience and advanced education. Driven leader capable of exceptional vendor and event management within budget and timeline requirements. Versatile team member who approaches every project and challenge with a diverse toolkit of ideas and problem-solving techniques.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Marketing Manager**

Global Beauty Group

August 2015 – Present

Manage several brands, each with a unique customer base and sales channel, collaborating with brand leaders, suppliers, sales teams and buyers to grow product offering in response to market trends.

- Identify third party companies for promotions and partnerships to drive sales through new customer contact
- Manage email campaigns through Critical Impact and direct web administrator on eCommerce strategy to improve content, layout and sales

### **Marketing Communications Manager**

Airgas

*October* 2013 – *July* 2015

Central resource for marketing communications initiatives and tradeshow program. Collaborated with multiple market segment leaders and teams to create a wide range of materials specific to their unique audiences, including presentation decks, sales literature, mailings and other promotional materials.

- Responsible for key vendor management, including printers, tradeshow companies and ad agencies. Built, maintained and expanded marketing communications programs and tools utilized by a national sales force
- Oversaw creation and distribution of tradeshow graphics, direct mail, sell sheets, advertising and on-hold messaging with particular attention paid to maintaining brand integrity

### **Senior Marketing Communications Specialist**

Airga

*January 2010 – October 2013* 

Developed internal and external communications including meeting materials, newsletters, executive memos, biographies and the annual report. Assisted in corporate initiative development and rollout with a focus on communication strategy.

- Developed, expanded and protected the Airgas brand through marketing communications programs, including tradeshow, meeting and event planning
- Worked with strategic account teams entering newly defined markets as well as local field representatives and store managers in local markets nationwide

## **Marketing Communications Specialist**

Airgas

May 2008 – January 2010

Assisted in managing day-to-day relationships with outside vendors and internal marketing professionals across the company and its various business units.

- Assisted in organization of national award ceremonies, tradeshows and meetings
- Developed materials regarding corporate and social responsibility initiatives including environmental accountability and veteran recruiting as well as newsletters and advertisements